# Fanyi Xiao

CONTACT Information 2078 Academic Surge University of California Davis Davis, CA 95616, USA WWW: fanyix.cs.ucdavis.edu Mobile: 949-491-2293

E-mail: fanyix.cs@gmail.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research interests lie in computer vision. I am also broadly interested in all AI/machine learning topics that could help achieve better visual perception for machines. I have research experiences in object recognition/detection, visual attributes and video data modelling. Currently, I am particularly interested in *mining* weakly supervised dataset for the purpose of exploring, organizing, and harvesting useful information that could help improve various vision tasks.

**EDUCATION** 

## University of California Davis, Computer Science Dept., Davis, CA, USA

Ph.D. student, Computer Science

• Advisor: Prof. Yong Jae Lee

## Carnegie Mellon University, Robotics Institute, Pittsburgh, PA, USA

M.S., Robotics, 2014

• Advisors: Prof. Martial Hebert and Prof. Yaser Sheikh

• Thesis: Model Recommendation for Large Scale Exemplar-based Object Detection

## Central South University, Computer Science Department, Changsha, China

B.S., Computer Science, 2012

• Thesis: Facial Expression Analysis with Active Appearance Model

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] Fanyi Xiao and Yong Jae Lee. Track and segment: An iterative unsupervised approach for video object proposals. In *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR), 2016. (Spotlight presentation).
- [2] Krishna Singh, Fanyi Xiao, and Yong Jae Lee. Track and transfer: Watching videos to simulate strong human supervision for weakly-supervised object detection. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2016.
- [3] Fanyi Xiao and Yong Jae Lee. Discovering the spatial extent of relative attributes. In *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2015. (Oral presentation).
- [4] Fanyi Xiao and Martial Hebert. Efficient model evaluation with bilinear separation model. In Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2015.
- [5] Fanyi Xiao, Martial Hebert, Yaser Sheikh, Yair Movshovitz-Attias, Mei Chen, and Denver Dash. Runtime model recommendation for exemplar-based object detection. Technical report, Robotics Institute, Carnegie Mellon University, 2014.
- [6] Zhiding Yu, Chunjing Xu, Deyu Meng, Fanyi Xiao, Wenbo Liu, and Jianzhuang Liu. Transitive distance clustering with k-means duality. In *International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2014.
- [7] Iljoo Baek, Taylor Stine, Denver Dash, Fanyi Xiao, Yaser Ajmal Sheikh, Yair Movshovitz-Attias, Mei Chen, Martial Hebert, and Takeo Kanade. Physical querying with multi-modal sensing. In Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2014.

#### AWARDS

- Graduate Fellowship, UC Davis, 2015
- AWS Research Grant (\$10000), Amazon Web Services, Inc., 2015
- Graduate Research Assistantship, CMU, 2013-2014
- Excellent Undergraduate Thesis, CSU, 2012
- Top Grade Scholarship (University-wide highest honor, 0.8%), CSU, 2010
- Sunward Scholarship (0.4%), Sunward Corporation, 2010
- National Scholarship (1%), Ministry of Education of China, 2009
- 1st Grade Scholarship (6%), CSU, 2009

#### EXPERIENCE

## Disney Research, Pittsburgh, PA

Summer Intern

June 2016 - Sept 2016

• Work with Dr. Leonid Sigal on weakly supervised vision-language alignment problem. [In Submission]

## University of California Davis, Davis, CA

Graduate Student Researcher

Sept 2014 - Present

- Design of a video object proposal algorithm, which takes a video as input, to output proposals that are either object-like or having distinct motion against the background. [CVPR 2016]
- Proposed a weakly supervised object detection algorithm that transfers tracked object tubes from video, i.e., exploiting the extra motion information, to improve object localization. Achieved state-of-the-art performance on PASCAL VOC 2007/2010 in the weakly supervised setting. [CVPR 2016]
- Development of a visual attribute mining algorithm which takes the dataset with image-level relative attribute annotation as the input to automatically discover visual elements corresponding to semantic attributes. [ICCV 2015]

#### Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Graduate Research Assistant

Sept 2012 - June 2014

- Proposed the *Bilinear Separation Model* to approximate the exemplar models with low-rank estimators which are learnt by optimizing a task-specific maxmargin formulation. [WACV 2015]
- Development of a framework which uses *collaborative filtering* to recommend object detection models for testing images during runtime to avoid exhaustive search, thus scale up the exemplar-based object detection. [CMU TR 2014]

#### Intel Science and Technology Center, Pittsburgh, PA

Student Researcher

Sept 2012 - Aug 2013

 Development of a multi-modal sensing retailing assistant named "Marvin". Lead developer of the visual recognition module. [WACV 2014]

## Central South University, Changsha, China

Undergraduate Senior Thesis

Sept 2011 - June 2012

• Implementation and analysis of a facial expression classification system based on the Active Appearance Model (AAM) representation.

SKILLS

- Programming: Python, C/C++, Lua, MATLAB, Java
- Misc: Torch7, Caffe, LINUX, LATEX

# GRADUATE COURSES

- CMU: Computer Vision / Machine Learning / Convex Optimization Math Fundamentals for Robotics / Learning-based Methods in Vision Mechanics of Manipulation
- UC Davis: Visual Recognition / Semantics of Programming Languages

SERVICE

 $\bullet$  Reviewer, Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2015–2017